# ---- SURBHI RAUTJI ------ SOFTWARE ENGINEER AND OA SPECIALIST

## **CONTACT**

- 669-224-9849
- SURBHIRAUTJI23
- Surbhi.rautji@gmail.com
  - surbhirautji23@github.io

## **PROFILE**

MASTER'S IN SOFTWARE ENGINNEERING DEGREE HOLDER AND 3+ YEARS OF EXPERIENCE AS SOFWARE ENGINEERING WITH FORTE IN QA ENGINEERING PRACTICES.

KEY CONTRIBUTOR TO HANUMAYAMA SOFTWARE QA ENGINEERING AND DEVELOPMENT PRACTICES FOR CLIENTS AND PROJECTS LIKE 3K TECHNOLOGIES AND DAIRY ANALYTICS, SANJEEVANI APPLICATION, ETC, RESPECTIVELY.

EXPERTISE IN SELENIUM JAVASCRIPT, SELENIUM SERVER AND RC, JAVA, CSS, MYSQL, FUNATIONAL TESTING, REGRESSION TESTING, API TESTING, JUNIT, JIRA., AGILE, TEST PLANNING, DOCUMENTATION, TROUBLESHOOTING AND DEBUGGING, ETC.

#### **SKILLS**

- JAVASCRIPT, JAVA, MYSQL,
  POSTGRESQL, ORACLE 10G, JQUERY
- SELENIUM WEB DRIVER, SELENIUM RC,
  JUNIT, AUTOMATION TESTING, TEST NG LISTENERS, CSS SELECTORS, XPATH
  LOCATORS, ADVANCED REST CLIENT,
  POSTMAN, AWS, MICROSOFT AZURE
- GIT, MAVEN, GRADLE, NPM, JIRA,
  BUGZILLA, CONFLUENCE, SHELL, UNIX,
  JENKINS, AGILE, ECLIPSE, INTELLIJ
  VSCODE

## **EXPERIENCE**

# SOFTWARE QA ENGINEER, (CONTRACT), 3K TECHNOLOGIES

MARCH 2019 - JUNE 2019

- Setting up Active monitoring, Event Hub, Connected Factories on Azure
- Developed event trigger gathering scripts in Javascript and Java
- Validated data points on Cosmos DB using. Selenium and SQL driver
- Create QA automation end to end framework using Selenium Webdriver
- Performed Quality Test and created quality report for the application
  Performed Data Validation testing for both input and output pipeline.
- Performed Data and API validation testing, ensuring accuracy of the data

Microsoft Azure | IOT Connected Factory | IOT Hub | Event Hub | Remote Monitoring Accelerator | Selenium Database Validation | Azure Cosmos DB | Microsoft Azure Data Lake | Java | C# | JavaScript | Selenium WebDriver based Test E2E Automation

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER, HANUMAYAMA INNOVATIONS AND TECHNOLOGIES

SEPT 2016 - PRESENT

- Agile development and testing of dairy analytics, sensor motion analytics application for monitoring cattle movement and dynamics.
- Conduct native mobile apps testing using tools like Appium for targeted devices like Google Pixel (1st version), apple iPhone 6, 6s, 7 variants.
- Developed QA automation framework with Selenium Web Driver and POM
- Enhanced framework automated data validation using JUnit and Selenium
- Maintain CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins, Scripting and Version Control
- Collecting functional and non-functional requirement in collaboration with Business Analysts, Project Managers and various another stakeholder
- Define and develop use cases, test scenarios, test strategies and test script

#### **EDUCATION**

#### SAN JOSE STATE UNIVERSITY

AUG 2014- MAY 2016

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

# AMITY UNIVERSITY, NOIDA

AUG 2008 - JUNE 2012

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

#### **PUBLICATION**

Immersive visualization of Remote Sensing Data, Signal & Image Processing: An International Journal (SIPIJ) Vol.4, No.5, October 2013

Behavioural Biometrics and Cognitive Security Authentication Comparison Study, Advanced Computing: An International Journal (ACIJ), Vol.4, No.6, November 2013

Cognitive Secure Shield – A Machine Learning Enabled Threat Shield For Resource Combined IOT Devices, S. Rautji, C. Vupplapatti, C. Chauhan, 10.1109/ICMLA.2018.00175, IEEE , 17-20 Dec. 2018

- Generating test coverage report after every testing cycle, presenting acceptance levels, coverage percentage and various testing meta data information.
- Contributed towards front end development of the Dairy analytics web application and company marketing website.
- Created and maintained test cases for Hanuinnotech.com in TestRail and performed web UI functional, regression, and integration testing.
- Provide accessibility and support to business analysts and sales engineer personals in performing user acceptance testing both internally and externally.
- Participate in bug triage meetings, collaborating with developers and managers for the prioritization of bugs and incidents, and help developers in reproducing bug origination scenarios and performing the root cause analysis.

HTML 5 | SCSS | CSS 3 | Java | MySQL | Bootstrap 3.3.2 | AWS | Atlassian Confluence | Selenium Web Driver | JMeter | Atlassian Jira | Bugzilla | TestRail

#### SOTWARE ENGINEER INTERN, NETSCOUT SYSTEMS

AUG 2015 - NOV 2015

- Testing and debugging the application, maintain issue metrics and creating visualization to do better analysis of the applications.
- Data parsing using Java, SQL and JavaScript for alerting engine nGeniusONE (Analytical application) for packet capture and packet analytics appliance.
- Data parsing for nDD (nGenius Database Deployment Cloud based application for nGenius Server Deployment at customer sites).
- Collected Data from various alert systems in XML format to parse it than organize and store the relevant information into PostgreSQL.
- Created the SQL code generator based on the input response generated from the alert system engine.
- Perform database validation on the database data processed through DML and DDL statements generated by the parsers.

#### SALES OPERATION ENGINEER, ORACLE CORPORATION

FEB 2013 - FEB 2014

- Interviewed stakeholders to gather pre-purchase requirements or the application feature feedbacks.
- Collected requirements on what product services would different government organizations across states of India would be interested in or if they hold any proposals on the requirements.
- Translated stakeholder requirements to Engineering and PM team into different tangible deliverables such as functional specifications, use cases, workflow/process diagrams, data flow/data model diagrams using Visio and Lucid Chart.
- Monitor, identify and troubleshoot issues for partner integrations for Oracle ERP Solutions.
- Maintaining weekly team activity reports and reporting summarized outcomes of the weekly activities to the Director of Sales Operations.
- Supported and collaborated in SDLC during different phases such as analysis, design, and testing. We used Confluence and Jira for project tracking.
- Quality assurance and conducting A/B testing of the products, and record maintenance of trial testing phases.
- Preparing summary, graphical representations and visualization using applications like tableau to represent the most important featured information.
- Contributed in improving and incrementing the product sales percentage, while in my tenure, by approximately 8%.
- Managed and merged large data sources and created visualizations to aid in sales pattern understanding; performed pattern recognition and learning.